const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following will not be a clinical finding in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Cough with sputum","bool":false},{"option":"Breathing through pursed lips","bool":false},{"option":"Wheezing","bool":false},{"option":"Splenomegaly","bool":true},{"option":"Weight loss","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following features, according to Light's criteria, is suggestive of exudative effusion?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH : serum LDH ratio > 0.6","bool":true},{"option":"Protein content of fluid < 30 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH < 2/3 of upper limit of normal serum LDH","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid protein : serum protein ratio < 0.5","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid glucose is higher than serum glucose","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is true about adipocere?","answers":[{"option":"Adipoceres always have a hard and cracked appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Caused by hydrolysis and hydrogenation","bool":true},{"option":"Cold temperature favors adipocere formation","bool":false},{"option":"Anaerobic conditions inhibit adipocere","bool":false},{"option":"Highly acidic soil prevents adipocere formation","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of these is not a feature seen in the eyes after death?","answers":[{"option":"Flaccidity of the eyeball","bool":false},{"option":"Gradual decline in vitreal potassium levels","bool":true},{"option":"Cattle trucking of retinal vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Taches noires on the sclera","bool":false},{"option":"Opacity of the cornea","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following tuberculosis drugs causes vestibular toxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is a second-line tuberculosis drug?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":true},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"If a person stands behind a thin cotton curtain, which radiation will he be protected from?","answers":[{"option":"Neutron","bool":false},{"option":"X-Ray","bool":false},{"option":"Beta","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the optimum temperature range for putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"60 °F and 100 °F","bool":false},{"option":"50 °F and 100 °F","bool":false},{"option":"80 °F and 90 °F","bool":false},{"option":"70 °F and 110 °F","bool":false},{"option":"70 °F and 100 °F","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is nosocomial pneumonia also known as?","answers":[{"option":"Atypical pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchopneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Hospital acquired pneumonia","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of community-acquired pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Legionella pneumophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is the first to undergo putrefaction after death?","answers":[{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":true},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"In which of the following diseases does the total lung capacity decrease?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What does Casper's dictum mean?","answers":[{"option":"Degree of mutilation","bool":false},{"option":"Cause of death","bool":false},{"option":"Rate of putrefaction","bool":true},{"option":"Time of death","bool":false},{"option":"Cause of putrefaction","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Curschmann spirals are a classical histopathological finding of which disease?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What are Charcot-Leyden crystals composed of?","answers":[{"option":"Silica fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophil proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Aggregates of calcium and protein","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Lysozyme","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"A 30-year-old female receiving anti-tuberculosis drugs complains of disturbance in vision and loss of visual acuity. Which of the following drugs would have caused this?","answers":[{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Cycloserine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"A dead body is discovered lying hidden amongst bushes in a supine position, with postmortem lividity fully established, and black in color. In the given scenario, which area of the body will not demonstrate the postmortem lividity?","answers":[{"option":"Hands","bool":false},{"option":"Sacral region","bool":false},{"option":"Back of ears","bool":false},{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital scalp","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the mechanism of action of methylxanthines?","answers":[{"option":"Activation of adenosine receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":true},{"option":"Activation of phosphodiesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in cGMP","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is acid rain caused by?","answers":[{"option":"Global warming","bool":false},{"option":"Increased carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Increased sulfur dioxide","bool":true},{"option":"Cow dung","bool":false},{"option":"Coal","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"A false negative purified protein derivative (PPD) test is NOT found in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"In newborns","bool":false},{"option":"Prior Bacille Calmette-Guérin (BCG) vaccination","bool":true},{"option":"In Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) positive tests","bool":false},{"option":"In malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"In malnutrition","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about smokers' macrophages?","answers":[{"option":"Finely granular iron may be seen in cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Feature of desquamative interstitial pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Dusty brown pigment in macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Presenting symptom is dyspnea and productive cough","bool":true},{"option":"Surfactant found in phagocytic vacuoles","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What kind of emphysema occurs in coal workers pneumoconiosis?","answers":[{"option":"Interstitial","bool":false},{"option":"Paraseptal","bool":false},{"option":"Panacinar","bool":false},{"option":"Centriacinar","bool":true},{"option":"Diffuse","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is the narrowest part of the pediatric airway?","answers":[{"option":"Larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Subglottic area","bool":false},{"option":"Cricoid ring","bool":true},{"option":"Glottis","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the most common site of lung cancer metastasis?","answers":[{"option":"Hilar lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenals","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Brain","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common occupational lung disease?","answers":[{"option":"Progressive massive fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":true},{"option":"Asymptomatic anthracosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Farmer's lung","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which type of hypersensitivity is being displayed in a positive Mantoux test?","answers":[{"option":"Type III","bool":false},{"option":"Type IV","bool":true},{"option":"Type II","bool":false},{"option":"Type I","bool":false},{"option":"Type VI","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following anti-tuberculosis drugs causes ototoxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following are avoided during chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Long-acting beta-agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Anticholinergics","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs","bool":true},{"option":"Short-acting beta-agonists","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common cancer that can metastasize to the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Liver cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Skin cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Breast cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Bone cancer","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following anti-tuberculous drugs is bactericidal?","answers":[{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Para amino salicylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":true},{"option":"Cycloserine","bool":false},{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is not associated with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Muscle wasting","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic liver disease","bool":true},{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Regarding laryngeotracheobronchitis, the most frequently observed radiological finding is:","answers":[{"option":"Ragged tracheal border","bool":false},{"option":"Thumb sign at epiglottis","bool":false},{"option":"Thickened nasopharyngeal space","bool":false},{"option":"Steeple sign","bool":true},{"option":"Normal","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"The type of asphyxia that is associated with anesthesia and surgical maneuvers is termed as:","answers":[{"option":"Mechanical asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Iatrogenic asphyxia","bool":true},{"option":"Clinical asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Pathological asphyxia","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What does the common radiological finding in the case of epiglottitis show?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray neck AP-view reveals \" steeple sign\"","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral x-ray of neck reveal \"steeple sign\"","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral nonhomogeneous infiltrations in both lungs with shifting of trachea on right side","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray chest shows bilateral hilar infiltration with shifting of trachea toward left side","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral x-ray of neck reveal \"thumb printing sign\"","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the cause of death in the peculiar condition termed as 'café coronary'?","answers":[{"option":"Asphyxia","bool":true},{"option":"Eating in a café","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty meals","bool":false},{"option":"Fish","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardial Infarction","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Where is the first sign of internal putrefaction seen?","answers":[{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Under surface of the liver","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"In which of the following disease, FEV1/FVC below 0.7 with an increased total lung capacity, is seen?","answers":[{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive lung disease","bool":true}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the method of action of montelukast?","answers":[{"option":"Cytokine receptor anatognist","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits the cysteinyl leukotriene CysLT1 receptor","bool":true},{"option":"Cytokine receptor agonist","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene receptor agonist","bool":false},{"option":"Prevents the release of granules from mast cells","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"A 55-year-old patient suffering from persistent dry cough for the last 2-months due to unknown reasons wants to get a drug without having constipating effects. Which of the following would you prescribe?","answers":[{"option":"Pholcodine","bool":false},{"option":"Codeine","bool":false},{"option":"Dextromethorphan","bool":true},{"option":"Physostigmine","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocodone","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is an important microscopical feature of acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS)?","answers":[{"option":"Diffuse septal fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse interstitial fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse alveolar damage","bool":true},{"option":"Diffuse bronchiolar damage","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse bronchoalveolar damage","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the maximum volume of air that can be expelled after normal expiration?","answers":[{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":true},{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is false about transudative effusion?","answers":[{"option":"Protein content is <3 g/dL","bool":false},{"option":"Serum LDH ratio is >0.6","bool":true},{"option":"Specific gravity is <1.015","bool":false},{"option":"Occurs mostly in congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Appearance is colourless","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of transudative pleural effusion?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural fluid to serum LDH ratio < 0.6","bool":false},{"option":"Specific gravity of fluid is less than 1.102","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid to serum protein ratio < 0.5","bool":false},{"option":"Protein content is > 3 g/dl","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH < 2/3 Serum LDH Upper Limit of Normal","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is an interferon-gamma release assay used to diagnose?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis disease","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis infection","bool":false},{"option":"Latent tuberculosis infection","bool":true},{"option":"Atypical pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the drug of choice for the treatment of bacterial pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Aminoglycosides","bool":false},{"option":"Fluoroquinolones","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillins","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalosporins","bool":false},{"option":"Macrolides","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the most common lung tumor in non-smokers?","answers":[{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Highest p53 mutations are found in which type of lung cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoma in situ","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What causes epithelial damage in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Major basic protein","bool":true},{"option":"Eotaxin","bool":false},{"option":"Bradykinin","bool":false},{"option":"Chemokines","bool":false},{"option":"Increased mucus","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which carcinoma secretes antidiuretic hormone and adrenocorticotropic hormone?","answers":[{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic of septic shock?","answers":[{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory distress","bool":false},{"option":"Alkalosis","bool":true},{"option":"End organ failure","bool":false},{"option":"Hypovolemia","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What are the acute effects of poor illumination/lighting?","answers":[{"option":"Minor nystagmus","bool":false},{"option":"Headache and eye pain","bool":true},{"option":"Fatigue","bool":false},{"option":"Blurred vision","bool":false},{"option":"Discomfort","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"How is an epiglottis infection treated?","answers":[{"option":"Oral antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Racemic epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous antibiotics","bool":true},{"option":"Antiviral medications","bool":false},{"option":"Mist therapy","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is not seen in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchial breathing","bool":true},{"option":"Episodic dyspnea","bool":false},{"option":"Nocturnal cough","bool":false},{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Wheezing","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is true about rigor mortis?","answers":[{"option":"It is also called instantaneous rigor","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It is the stiffening of body muscles after death","bool":true},{"option":"It is called false mortis","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs 48 hours after death","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic of small cell carcinoma of the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Lepidic growth pattern of tall columnar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Lepidic growth pattern of cuboidal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Undifferentiated malignant epithelial tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Keratin pearls and intercellular bridges","bool":false},{"option":"Round or oval cells with scant cytoplasm and nuclear molding (salt and pepper appearance)","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is not associated with diffuse parenchymal lung diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Dry cough","bool":false},{"option":"Productive cough","bool":true},{"option":"Shortness of breath","bool":false},{"option":"Joint pain","bool":false},{"option":"Clubbing","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is used to determine ventilation abnormalities?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Total lung capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false},{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Forced expiratory volume","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Asbestosis is not associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchial asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural plaques","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"A coal mine worker develops chest pain which decreases their ability to work. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Siderosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Farmer's lung","bool":false},{"option":"Coal workers' pneumoconiosis","bool":true},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the best indicator of air pollution?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Methane","bool":false},{"option":"Smoke, suspended particles and sulfur dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Sulphur dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Particulate matter","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a complication of pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuritis","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchogenic carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Empyema","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is meant by ergonomics?","answers":[{"option":"Fitting the worker to the job","bool":false},{"option":"Fitting the job to the surroundings","bool":false},{"option":"Fitting worker to the surroundings","bool":false},{"option":"Fitting the surroundings to the worker","bool":false},{"option":"Fitting the job to the worker","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the below enlisted is the most significant occupational hazard from long-term ionizing radiation exposure?","answers":[{"option":"Hair loss","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased sperm","bool":false},{"option":"Flushed skin","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic changes","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased libido","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What occupational hazard is associated with welding?","answers":[{"option":"Conjuctivitis","bool":true},{"option":"Gingivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuritis","bool":false},{"option":"Carditis","bool":false},{"option":"Orchitis","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of bacterial pneumonia in children?","answers":[{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Legionella","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the pathology of bronchiectasis?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic pyogenic infections","bool":false},{"option":"Type I hypersensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Increased ciliary movement","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic necrotizing infections","bool":true},{"option":"Acute necrotizing infections","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"When is a gastric lavage contraindicated?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin overdose","bool":false},{"option":"Carbolic acid poisioning","bool":false},{"option":"Iron tablet overdose","bool":false},{"option":"Blood meal","bool":false},{"option":"Corrosive poisoning","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What can a saddle embolus lead to?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Sudden death","bool":true},{"option":"Nose bleed","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Chest pain","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is Mikulicz syndrome characterized by?","answers":[{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the thorax","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the perineum","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the head and neck","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is centriacinar emphysema caused by?","answers":[{"option":"Smoking","bool":true},{"option":"Radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Wool","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":false},{"option":"Beryllium","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"ICU admission for a patient with pneumonia is indicated with which CURB-65 score?","answers":[{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"3 or more","bool":true},{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"4 or more","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What level of the respiratory tract is choking seen at?","answers":[{"option":"Nose and mouth","bool":false},{"option":"Main bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Glottis","bool":true},{"option":"Larynx","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following arteries is most commonly blocked in autopsy in case of coronary atherosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"Circumflex artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right marginal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left subclavian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right coronary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior descending artery","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which is the most common lung cancer seen in women?","answers":[{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchioalveolar carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"A 50-year-old male works at a coal mine for the past 7 years. He is also a  smoker. He presents with complaints of progressive dyspnea and pulmonary hypertension. His biopsy shows extensive carbon-laden macrophages with extensive fibrosis. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Coal workers' pneumoconiosis","bool":true},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"Farmer's lung","bool":false},{"option":"Siderosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"A 2-year-old boy is brought to the clinic with a barking cough and hoarseness of voice. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute pharyngitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute epiglottitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsillitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute laryngotracheitis","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following are complications of asbestosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiac arrhythmias","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural and lung cancers","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is a complication of silicosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Coughing","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of these is not a risk factor for tuberculosis in children?","answers":[{"option":"Close contact with affected person","bool":false},{"option":"Enclosed, poorly ventilated spaces","bool":false},{"option":"Positive skin test","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac problems","bool":true},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is true about terbutaline?","answers":[{"option":"It is a vasoconstrictor","bool":false},{"option":"It is a beta-2 antagonist","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It is a bronchodilator","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following investigations are done to confirm tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Purified protein derivative skin test","bool":false},{"option":"Lung biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"3 morning sputum samples taken for sputum culture","bool":true},{"option":"Sputum staining","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is a differentiating point between chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchodilator reversibility >15% in COPD","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma is a restrictive lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchodilator reversibility >15% in asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Allergic rhinitis is a feature of asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Diurnal variation is present in COPD","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the best first-line diagnostic test for pulmonary embolism?","answers":[{"option":"Arterial blood gases","bool":false},{"option":"Electrocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"Computerized tomography (CT) pulmonary angiography","bool":true},{"option":"Chest x-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulation profile","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is the mechanism of action of methylxanthines?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of phosphodiesterase","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of phospholipase C","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of adenosine receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is red hepatization caused by?","answers":[{"option":"Enzymatic digestion of exudate by macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Exudate with fibrin, white blood cells, and lysed red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Exudate with fibrin, bacteria, red blood cells, and white blood cells","bool":true},{"option":"Transudate with fibrin, bacteria, and red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Exudate with mostly bacteria","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"After the exhumation of a body, the gender is determined from which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Fingers","bool":false},{"option":"Ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvis","bool":true},{"option":"Femur","bool":false},{"option":"Skull","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"A woman is hypoglycemic and shows some respiratory signs. Upon investigation, she has a tumor that is attached to the pleura with a pedicle. What is the most likely condition?","answers":[{"option":"Solitary fibrous tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Histoplasmosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metastasis","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Sociable fibrous tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following methods is used to make a diagnosis of sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Gastric lavage","bool":false},{"option":"Sputum culture","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoalveolar lavage","bool":false},{"option":"Transbronchial biopsy","bool":true},{"option":"Chest x-ray","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What type of antidote prevents the absorption of poison?","answers":[{"option":"Physiologic","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanical","bool":true},{"option":"Chemical","bool":false},{"option":"Universal","bool":false},{"option":"Biological","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which interleukin is responsible for eosinophilia in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"IL-4","bool":false},{"option":"IL-5","bool":true},{"option":"IL-10","bool":false},{"option":"IL-1","bool":false},{"option":"IL-8","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What leads to icterus?","answers":[{"option":"Bilirubin deposition in the sclera","bool":true},{"option":"Bilirubin deposition in the ears","bool":false},{"option":"Bilirubin deposition in the skin","bool":false},{"option":"Bilirubin deposition in the stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Bilirubin deposition in the heart","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is the best indicator for a shock?","answers":[{"option":"Seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Bradycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Fever","bool":false},{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotension","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which organs are affected by sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"All of them","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the most common preservative used for the preservation of viscera?","answers":[{"option":"Bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium chloride","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Dihydrogen monoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfuric acid","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the mechanism of action of corticosteroids?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of inflammatory eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of inflammatory macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of inflammatory cytokines","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of inflammatory neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Attenuation of inflammatory cytokines","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"A diver has a condition that arises from dissolved gases coming out of solution into bubbles upon depressurization of the body. What is this condition known as?","answers":[{"option":"Drowning","bool":false},{"option":"Cow's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Diving disease","bool":false},{"option":"Caisson disease","bool":true},{"option":"Carrion disease","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is not associated with paraneoplastic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Subacute sensory neuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellar degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Lambert-Eaton syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Guillain-Barre syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Stiff-man syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is an example of a negative autopsy?","answers":[{"option":"Vascular rejection of cardiac allograft","bool":false},{"option":"Asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Vagal inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Penetrating fragment injuries in explosion","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following organisms is responsible for putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium welchii","bool":true},{"option":"Listeria monocytogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Spirochaetes","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydiae","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"What is the first external sign of putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"Distension","bool":false},{"option":"Postmortem luminescence","bool":false},{"option":"Marbling of skin","bool":false},{"option":"Greenish discoloration over the right iliac fossa","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is a long-acting beta-agonist?","answers":[{"option":"Metaproterenol","bool":false},{"option":"Tiotropium","bool":false},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"Salmeterol","bool":true},{"option":"Ipratropium","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is a rare site of lung cancer metastasis?","answers":[{"option":"Kidney","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal glands","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2017","question":"Which of the following is the best X-ray view for pneumothorax?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroanterior","bool":true},{"option":"Anteroposterior","bool":false}]}]
export default arr